Guide to the John B. Reubens Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
John B. Reubens papers
1902-2000
1952-1998
YCAL MSS 686
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
11.21
(12 boxes)
Correspondence, writings, subject files, notebooks and slides.
Reubens, John B.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Ragen MacKenzie on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2000.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 12 (computer disk): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
John B. Reubens
John B. Reubens, born July 11, 1917 in New York City to Raymond and Harriet (Stern) Reubens, was educated at the Horace Mann School (1935) in New York, Yale University (1939), and Columbia University (1942). After earning his law degree in 1942 he entered the family law firm of Stern and Reubens. Reubens joined the U.S. Army the same year and served in the 82nd Airborne and Sixth Armored Division Infantry until 1945. He returned to law practice from 1945 to 1952, when he moved his family to Colorado Springs, Colorado. For the next 40 years he worked in various writing-related jobs, as a reporter, editor, and contributing writer at newspapers and managing editor for engineering and technical magazines. Reubens also wrote articles on fishing and fly fishing, fiction, and film scripts. After spending time in Mexico during the 1960s and 1970s, Reubens and his family settled in Montana in 1978, where he wrote a weekly column for a Livingston paper and advocated for local environmental concerns. He and his wife Madonna "Hap" Curran had small roles in the popular 1992 film A River Runs Through It, filmed in parts of Montana and Wyoming. Reubens died July 1, 1999 in Livingston, Montana.
Biographical information taken from obituary published in the Livingston Enterprise, July 15, 1999.
Scope and Contents
The John B. Reubens papers contains material documenting the professional life of American author and editor John B. Reubens. Reubens settled in the American West after serving in the U.S. Army in the 1940s, and the papers document his professional activities as a newspaper reporter, technical writer, and author from the 1950s onward. Materials include drafts of writings, correspondence, personal papers, and subject files on such topics as fishing and fly fishing and environmental issues in Montana and Wyoming.
Arrangement
Organized into seven groupings: Writings, 1968-1997. Writings on Fishing, 1960-1990. General Correspondence, 1952-2000. Personal/Family Correspondence, 1942-1995. Writings on Fly Fishing and Related Articles, 1949-1977. Notebooks, 1940-1993. Subject Files and Writings, 1902-1999.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Environmentalism -- United States; Fishing -- United States; Fly fishing -- United States; Montana -- Environmental conditions; Wyoming -- Environmental conditions; Born digital; Electronic documents; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Reubens, John B.
- Writings, 1968-1997
  - Doubtful Legacy, 1986; 3 (Box 1)
  - Esmeralda, undated; 2 (Box 1)
  - El Fego Baca, 1975; 3 (Box 1)
  - Freedom Regained, undated; 3 (Box 1)
  - Invitation to Murder, 1987; 3 (Box 1)
  - Marlowe, 1998; 2 (Box 1)
  - Various Stories, 1968-1978; 3 (Box 1)
  - Against the Current, 1995; 5 (Box 2)
  - Bitter Fruit, 1995; 3 (Box 2)
  - Cookbook, 1965; 4 (Box 2)
  - Deadly Legacy, 1991; 3 (Box 2)
  - Delight in Battle, 1997; 2 (Box 2)
- Writings on Fishing, 1960-1990
  - Angler's Beat, 1968-1977 (Box 3)
  - Home Projects, Tool Ads, 1960-1990 (Box 3)
  - Fly Fishing Casting Tips, 1984-1991 (Box 3)
  - Fly Fishing Foreign, 1980-1999 (Box 3)
  - France, undated (Box 3)
  - Fish Management, 1987-1991 (Box 3)
- General Correspondence, 1952-2000
  - Avery, 1980-1995 (Box 3)
  - Belin, Don and Harriet, 1962-1993 (Box 3)
  - Birthday Cards, 1960-1993 (Box 3)
  - Bower, Bill and Lorraine, 1960-1995 (Box 3)
  - Bralower, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Cox, Charles and Kirsten, 1986-1993 (Box 3)
  - Crosswords, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Dirks, John and Mary, 1968-1999 (Box 3)
  - Eckhardt, Mac and Doris, 1981-1996 (Box 3)
  - Fasanella, Rocko and Marion, 1977-1999 (Box 3)
  - Frazier, William, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Gamboa, Fidel, 1976-1988 (Box 3)
  - Hadley, Arthur and Bush, George, 1992-1997 (Box 3)
  - Haigh-Brown, Valerie, 1952-1990 (Box 3)
  - Hamilburg, Michael, 1988-1996 (Box 3)
  - Howard, Mac, 1960-1990 (Box 3)
  - Howe, Dave, 1974-1981 (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Ben, 1972-1999 (Box 3)
  - Kelsey, Stephen, 1987-1992 (Box 3)
  - Kemp, Vivian, 1960-1980 (Box 3)
  - Knopf, Pat, 1953-1992 (Box 3)
  - Kustich, Jerry, 1983-1997 (Box 3)
  - Lorrey, Andrew, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Lorrey, Haidee, 1994-1996 (Box 3)
  - Lorrey, Jeannie, 1973-1994 (Box 3)
  - Lee-Ray, Jan, 1996-1998 (Box 4)
  - Livingston, Tom, 1980-1997 (Box 4)
  - Mann, David, 1971-1990 (Box 4)
  - McCowen, Margaret, 1970-1996 (Box 4)
  - McGuane, Thomas, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1987-2000 (Box 4)
  - Montana Friends, 1999 (Box 4)
  - McNulty, J. Munroe, 1983-198[?] (Box 4)
  - Murphy, Tom, 1981-1990 (Box 4)
  - Mueller, Sawyer, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Orr, Larry, 1969-1997 (Box 4)
  - Perry, William, 1980-1989 (Box 4)
  - Peterson, Beryl, 1980-1995 (Box 4)
  - Ramirez family, 1971-1997 (Box 4)
  - Shannon, William, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Sheffer, Craig, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Sprague, Mash, 1999; 2 (Box 4)
  - Starr, Roger, undated (Box 4)
  - Wenz, Skip, 1996; 3 (Box 4)
  - Woelfer, Emerson, 1967-1992 (Box 4)
  - Yale, 1999 (Box 4)
- Personal/Family Correspondence, 1942-1995
  - Military service and discharge, 1942 (Box 5)
  - Petition for bar admission, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Ailes, John, 1953-1987; 3 (Box 5)
  - Britton, Edgar, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Buchman, Harry, 1961-1982 (Box 5)
  - Lorrey, Jean, 1970-1979 (Box 5)
  - McClane, Al, 1970-1995 (Box 5)
  - McCue, George, 1962-1993 (Box 5)
  - Wright, Charles, 1979-1991 (Box 5)
- Writings on Fly Fishing and Related Articles, 1949-1977
  - Colorado Fishing Regulations, 1959-1976 (Box 5)
  - Field Notes, 1949-1953 (Box 5)
  - Sportsman's Corner, 1968-1977; 3 (Box 5)
  - Angler's Beat, 1957-1967; 4 (Box 5)
  - Hunting and fishing notes, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Note cards, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Paid in full, undated; 3 (Box 6)
- Notebooks, 1940-1993
  - Fly Patterns, 1980-1990; 2 (Box 6)
  - Montana Spring Creeks, 1986; 2 (Box 6)
  - Environmental Issues, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Forest Service Volumes 1-4, 1940-1980; 4 (Box 6)
  - General Fish Information, 1970-1990 (Box 6)
  - Notes (general), 1970-1990 (Box 6)
- Subject Files and Writings, 1902-1999
  - A to the Nth, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Against the Current, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Altered, Mutilated or Defaced, 1998 (Box 6)
  - American Rivers, 1995-1998 (Box 7)
  - Balanced is Better, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Banks and Banking, 1991-1993 (Box 7)
  - Baucus, Max, 1991-1997 (Box 7)
  - Bees Wax, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Bird and Animal Drawings, 1976-1999 (Box 7)
  - Bison, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Blowout, undated (Box 7)
  - Calabi, Syl, 1983-1998 (Box 7)
  - Candle Maker, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Cartoons, undated (Box 7)
  - Catalogue Running, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Catalogue, Angler's Art, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Catch and Release, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Caterpillar, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Certain Unpleasantness, 1992-1995 (Box 7)
  - Character Part, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Christmas Peril, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Clean Water, 1994-1996 (Box 7)
  - Common Cause, 1992-1995 (Box 7)
  - Correct Legislature, 1995 (Box 7)
  - County Commissioners, 1969-1996 (Box 7)
  - Covers, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Cracking the Refrigerator Code, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Criminal Roster, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Crossword Correspondence, 1988-1997 (Box 7)
  - Crossword Forms, undated (Box 7)
  - Congress-Reps, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Consumer's Handbook, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Construction Central States, 1965-1997; 2 (Box 7)
  - C.U.T. Prophet, 1987-1993 (Box 7)
  - Danger Sunshine, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Delight In Battle, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Decoys, undated (Box 7)
  - Ducks, 1981-1993 (Box 7)
  - Durango Story, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Ecological Approach, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Epidemics, 1992 (Box 7)
  - E-Mails, 1999 (Box 7)
  - Eyes Have It, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Federation of Fly Fishers, 1994 (Box 8)
  - F.E.R.C., 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Field and Stream, 1997 (Box 8)
  - Fish and Game Commissions, 1986-1996 (Box 8)
  - Fishing Spring Creeks, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Fishing Miscellaneous, 1988-1997 (Box 8)
  - Fishing Montana, 1978-1992 (Box 8)
  - Fly Fishing Refs, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Flying Suppliers, 1950-1999 (Box 8)
  - Flowing Gold, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Forestry Fraud, 1991-1993 (Box 8)
  - Forestry Management, 1988-1996 (Box 8)
  - Gingrich, 1994-1999 (Box 8)
  - Grand Canyon Trip, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Gray's Journal, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Grizzly Bears, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Henry's Fork Foundation, 1989-1995 (Box 8)
  - High County News, 1986-1994 (Box 8)
  - Hooked On Caddis, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Hot Chestnuts, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Humor, 1987-1996 (Box 8)
  - Humor, Miscellaneous, 1960-1990 (Box 8)
  - Humor, Pogo and Pfeiffer, 1960-1990 (Box 8)
  - Ideas Unfinished, undated (Box 8)
  - Invitation To Murder, 1987 (Box 8)
  - Jewelry, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Job Hunt, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Ladies of the Angle, undated (Box 8)
  - Lands End, 1987 (Box 8)
  - Leaders, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Limmericks, 1973-1985 (Box 8)
  - Long Way Down, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Luck of the Draw, 1996 (Box 8)
  - Magic Wands, 1987 (Box 9)
  - Mail Fraud, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Man Will Be Convicted, 1993-1994 (Box 9)
  - Map of Boulder, 1902 (Box 9)
  - Marketing, 1992-1997 (Box 9)
  - Marlowe, 1987-1999 (Box 9)
  - Marty Sherman, 1987-1997 (Box 9)
  - Matter of Choice, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Measure of the Year, 1979-1993 (Box 9)
  - Miles, undated (Box 9)
  - Ministry of Fear, 1991 (Box 9)
  - Mirada Larga Press, 1981-1998 (Box 9)
  - Missoula Carousel, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Mithra, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Modest Proposal, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Morrison Knudson, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Montana Regulations, 1984-1988 (Box 9)
  - Montana Environment, 1990-1999 (Box 9)
  - Montana Trout Foundation, 1989-1994 (Box 9)
  - Montana Alliance, 1989-1995 (Box 9)
  - Motion Picture-River Runs Through It: acting contracts, opening invitations, screenplay, final crew lists, newspaper articles on production, correspondence with Robert Redford, 1996-1997; 3 (Box 9)
  - Music to Buy, 1987 (Box 9)
  - National Parks, 1986-1998 (Box 9)
  - Nature Conservancy, 1988-1999 (Box 9)
  - Neat-Messy, undated (Box 9)
  - Neglected Genius, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Nick Lyons, 1983-1996 (Box 9)
  - No Spill Cement Holder, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Not the Khan, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Not the River, 1983 (Box 9)
  - Office Supplies, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Orvis, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Outdoor Fiction, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Overmuch Reading, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Paper Chase, 1987 (Box 9)
  - Parks, 1986-1996 (Box 9)
  - Park City Environmental Council, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Park County Weekly Articles, 1997-1998 (Box 9)
  - People For the American Way, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Personalities, 1989-1999 (Box 9)
  - Pesticides, 1968-1990 (Box 10)
  - Poetry, undated; 2 (Box 10)
  - Pollution Air, 1989-1998 (Box 10)
  - Pollution Water, 1969-1992 (Box 10)
  - Postage Due, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Pou-Pou, 1963 (Box 10)
  - Pretty Woman II, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Preserved In Amber, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Proper Credit, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Proposals for Aero Space, 1968; 2 (Box 10)
  - Publications List, undated (Box 10)
  - Range Conservation and Anti- Conservation, 1984-1998; 2 (Box 10)
  - Redford, 1995-1999 (Box 10)
  - Regional Rap, 1988-1991 (Box 10)
  - Restored Glory Railway Car, 1996 (Box 10)
  - Rest Stop, 1989 (Box 10)
  - Resume, 1976-1994 (Box 10)
  - Rifle Pointers, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Rowers, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Safety and Speed, 1978 (Box 10)
  - Salmon, 1990-1992 (Box 10)
  - School Board, 1983-1996 (Box 10)
  - Scientific Writing, 1965-1985 (Box 10)
  - Serpent's Tooth, undated (Box 10)
  - Shoshone River, 1994-1996 (Box 10)
  - Smallmouth of West Virginia, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Small Stream Addicts, 1993 (Box 10)
  - Smith, Daniel, 1998 (Box 10)
  - Smithsonian, 1998 (Box 10)
  - Souvenir Magazines Brochures, 1967-1976 (Box 10)
  - Speculator, 1996 (Box 10)
  - Spring Creek Restoration, 1996 (Box 10)
  - Suspect, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Syndication, 1981-1998 (Box 10)
  - To Ensure Proper Credit-RM, undated
    Conditions Governing Access
    Computer disk is restricted. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services.
    Scope and Contents
    2000-ycal-1107-r-0001: To Ensure Proper Credit-RM
  - Tag lines, 1994-1997 (Box 11)
  - Teaching Tolerance, 1993-1997 (Box 11)
  - Tear Sheets, 1954-1990 (Box 11)
  - Technical Writing, 1958-1968 (Box 11)
  - Theater Programs, 1980-1998 (Box 11)
  - Trains, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Travel Aid Supreme, undated (Box 11)
  - Treble Play, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Trout Spawned Dollars, 1986 (Box 11)
  - Tumbleweed Cartoons, 1980-1999 (Box 11)
  - Unlucky One, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Virginia City, 1995 (Box 11)
  - Vengeance, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Washroom Wipeout, 1997 (Box 11)
  - Wilderness Bill, 1992 (Box 11)
  - With My Own Hands, 1974 (Box 11)
  - Wilderness Association, 1993-1998 (Box 11)
  - Works, Nels, 1964-1979 (Box 11)
  - Writing A Better Paper, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Wyoming Sellout, 1975 (Box 11)
  - Yellowstone Threat, 1981-1995 (Box 11)
  - Yellowstone Task Force, 1997 (Box 11)
  - You Can Not Have My Rose Garden, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Empty folders, undated (Box 11)
  - Slides, 1973-1978; 2 (Box 11)
- Computer Media
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - TO ENSURE PROPER CREDIT - RM, 2000-ycal-1107-r-0001; 1 (Box 12)
    Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.